HIGH SEPTON: May the Warrior
grant him courage
and protect him in these perilous times.
May the Smith grant him strength
that he might bear this heavy burden
and may the Crone.
she that knows the fate of all men.
show him the path he must walk
and guide him through the dark places
that lie ahead.
In the light of the Seven.
I now proclaim
Tommen of the House Baratheon
First of His Name
King of the Andals and the First Men
and Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
Long may he reign!
ALL: Long may he reign!
(CHEERING)
Special day.
(CROWD CHATTING)
Your Grace.
-Your Grace.
There he is.
Long may he reign.
He sits the throne
like he was born to it.
Yes. He wasn't. though. was he?
No. he wasn't.
You still mourn for Joffrey?
He was my husband. My king.
He would have been your nightmare.
Your Grace. I feel--
You knew exactly what he was.
I did. too.
You never love anything in the world
the way you love your first child.
Doesn't matter what they do.
And what he did. it shocked me.
-Do you think I'm easily shocked?
-No.
The things he did shocked me.
He's only a boy.
A good boy. A decent boy.
He always has been.
Who was the last decent king. I wonder?
He could be the first man
who sits on that throne in 50 years
to actually deserve it.
It would be some consolation.
wouldn't it?
For all the horror that put him there.
He will need help...
if he's going to rule well.
He has you.
A mother is not enough.
You're still interested in being queen.
I take it?
(SCOFFS)
After all that's happened--
it sounds strange. I know. but I. uh--
I haven't even given any thought to it.
what comes next.
It would be a great honor. of course.
But I will have to speak to my father
about it.
Yes. speak to your father.
I'll speak to mine.
We may be faced with an alarming number
of weddings soon.
(CHUCKLES)
I won't even know what to call you.
Sister?
(SIGHS)
Or Mother?
(SCOFFS)
King Joffrey Baratheon is dead.
Murdered at his own wedding.
BARRISTAN: And we have taken
the Meereenese navy. Your Grace.
The Second Sons
took the Meereenese navy.
-Who told you to take the navy?
-No one.
So why did you do it?
I heard you liked ships.
-How many ships?
-93. Your Grace.
-How many men can they carry?
-9.300. not counting sailors.
Would that be enough
to take King's Landing?
The Lannisters have more.
BARRISTAN: They've been fighting
Joffrey's wars for years.
They're tired. dispersed.
And now their king is dead.
8.000 Unsullied. 2.000 Second Sons
sailing into Blackwater Bay
and storming the gates without warning.
It's hard to say. It could be enough.
But we're not fighting to make you
queen of King's Landing.
10.000 men can't conquer Westeros.
The old houses will flock to our queen
when she crosses the Narrow Sea.
The old houses will flock
to whichever side they think will win.
as they always have.
There's other news.
From Yunkai.
Without the Unsullied
to enforce your rule.
the Wise Masters
have retaken control of the city.
They've reenslaved
the freedmen who stayed behind
and sworn to take revenge against you.
And in Astapor.
the council you installed
to rule over the city
has been overthrown
by a butcher named Cleon
who's declared himself
"His Imperial Majesty."
Please leave me.
Not you. Jorah.
It appears my liberation of Slaver's Bay
isn't going quite as planned.
You could sail for Westeros
and leave it all behind.
A boy sits on the Iron Throne.
A boy many believe
to be a bastard with no right to it.
They've never been more vulnerable.
You counseled me against rashness
once in Qarth.
I didn't listen.
That all worked out well.
(CHUCKLES)
How can I rule seven kingdoms
if I can't control Slaver's Bay?
Why should anyone trust me?
Why should anyone follow me?
You're a Targaryen.
You're the Mother of Dragons.
I need to be more than that.
I will not let those I have freed
slide back into chains.
I will not sail for Westeros.
What. then?
I will do what queens do.
I will rule.
Pull up your hood.
A memorable shade.
But how would they know?
You know what kind of stories
poor men enjoy the most?
Ones about rich girls
they'll never meet.
Is this the only way into the Eyrie?
The mountains are impassable.
If you want to get to the Eyrie.
you need to go through the Bloody Gate.
It doesn't matter
how large your army is.
if you attack this gate.
you do it on this road.
three men abreast
and get slaughtered like goats.
The first Lords of the Vale
didn't have much.
but they had these mountains
and they knew how to use them.
And the fortress they built here
has never been overcome.
Not once in 1.000 years.
Know your strengths. use them wisely.
and one man can be worth 10.000.
KNIGHT: Who would pass the Bloody Gate?
Lord Petyr Baelish and his niece Alayne.
-Stand to.
-Stand to!
Welcome back. Lord Baelish.
(GATE CLANKING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Uncle Petyr!
LITTLEFINGER: My lord.
Oh.
I have brought you a gift.
-Lord Baelish.
-My lady.
-Look what Uncle Petyr brought me.
-A beautiful gift for a beautiful boy.
It's a pleasure to make
your acquaintance. Lady Arryn.
-My name is Al--
-Oh. do take down that hood. child.
Don't you think know who you are?
You think I'd let my intended
leave the Eyrie on urgent business
without knowing what that business was?
I let him go so he could bring you
here to me.
My flesh and blood.
It's wonderful to meet you. Aunt Lysa.
You mustn't call me that
in front of anyone else.
-Of course. I understand.
-No one can know you're here.
It would put us
in a very precarious position.
I would never say a thing.
The Lannisters want to destroy us.
They've been trying for years.
Now they know what it feels like.
Mummy said they killed your mother and
they chopped off your brother's head.
They did. and my father's.
They killed my father. too. with poison.
(SIGHS)
I wanted to make
the little Lannister baby man fly.
but Mother said I couldn't.
Make him fly?
Through the Moon Door.
(GIGGLES)
LYSA: And on top of everything else.
they made you marry that filthy troll.
They did. They made us both.
Lord Tyrion didn't want to.
LYSA: I don't believe that for a moment.
Did he force himself on you?
No. We never--
Good. Robin. this is your cousin Sansa.
But you're not to call her Sansa
in front of anyone
but Uncle Petyr and myself.
Do you understand?
Sansa. this is my son Robin.
It's a pleasure to meet you. Robin.
Robin. show Sansa to her chamber.
Take the back stairs.
Go. We'll speak soon.
What took you so long?
Arranging for the ascension
of King Tommen I.
extricating Sansa.
getting her here alive.
She's here. We've spent more than enough
time on her for one evening.
(SIGHS)
Let's get married tonight.
Ought we not...
inform the Lords of the Vale
about the ceremony?
There's only one Lord of the Vale.
The others can all hang.
Lurking and simpering
on the stairs like buzzards
the moment my husband died.
trying to get their claws in me.
-I do think that we could wait until--
-I'm done waiting. Petyr.
We had our wedding night many years ago.
-Don't you remember?
-Like it was yesterday.
What wife would do for you
the things I've done for you?
What wife would trust you
the way I've trusted you?
When you gave me those drops
and told me to pour them
into Jon's wine.
my husband's wine--
when you told me
to write a letter to Cat
telling her it was the Lannisters--
(MOANS)
The deed is done.
Faded into nothing.
Only speaking of it can make it real.
Tonight it is. then.
(CHUCKLES)
Let me bathe and dress for the occasion.
Once I'm presentable.
I'll call on the septon immediately.
I'm warning you.
I'm going to scream
when my husband makes love to me.
I'm going to scream so loud.
they'll hear me
clear across the Narrow Sea.
(LYSA SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING. MOANING)
(SCREAMING)
(MOANING. SCREAMING CONTINUES)
When will the wedding take place.
in your mind?
As soon as decency permits.
After we've allowed Tommen the
appropriate time to mourn his brother
and Margaery to mourn her husband.
-A fortnight?
-That seems reasonable.
No jugglers. no jousting dwarves.
no 77-course meals.
And your wedding to Loras?
Shortly after Tommen's.
-Shortly?
-A fortnight.
I know you don't like them.
I didn't like your husband.
Used to pat me on the back a lot.
I didn't trust him.
We had that in common.
You don't need to make formal alliances
with people you trust.
Then whom can we trust?
Ourselves alone.
The Tyrells
are our only true rivals
in terms of resources
and we need them on our side.
Robert wasn't particularly rich.
Robert had me funding him.
Wars swallow gold
like a pit in the earth.
I suppose that explains
why we did so well in the last one.
Do you know how much gold was mined
in the Westerlands this past year?
-Haven't a clue.
-Go on. your best guess.
Pounds. tons. ounces?
Doesn't matter. The answer is the same.
-That can't be.
-Our last working mine ran dry
three years ago.
Then how do we pay for anything?
The crown owes the Iron Bank of Braavos
a tremendous amount of money.
How much?
A tremendous amount.
There must be someone at the Iron Bank
you can speak to.
-come to some arrangement.
-The Iron Bank is the Iron Bank.
There is no someone.
Someone does work there.
It is comprised of people.
And a temple is comprised of stones.
One stone crumbles
and another takes its place.
And the temple holds its form
for 1.000 years or more.
That's what the Iron Bank is-- a temple.
We all live in its shadow
and almost none of us know it.
You can't run from them.
You can't cheat them.
You can't sway them with excuses.
If you owe them money
and you don't want to crumble yourself.
you pay it back.
Vesting the Tyrells in the crown
will help a great deal in this respect.
It's for the good of the family.
I understand that.
I'm not sure my brothers do.
I know you're building a strong case
against Tyrion.
And as a mother. that is your right.
But as a judge.
I cannot discuss the trial with you.
I respect that.
We don't need to discuss it.
The Lannister legacy
is the only thing that matters.
You've started wars
to protect this family.
Turned your back on Jaime for
refusing to contribute to its future.
What does Tyrion deserve
for lighting that future on fire?
ARYA: Joffrey.
Cersei.
Walder Frey.
Meryn Trant.
Tywin Lannister.
The Red Woman.
Beric Dondarrion.
Thoros of Myr.
Ilyn Payne. The Mountain.
Would you shut up?
I can't sleep until I say the names.
The names of every fucking person
in Westeros?
Only the ones I'm going to kill.
(THE HOUND SCOFFS)
Hate's as good a thing as any
to keep a person going.
Better than most.
We come across my brother.
maybe we can both cross a name
off our list.
If he were here right now.
what would you do?
I'd tell him to shut the fuck up
so I can get some sleep.
Go on. get it over with.
your list of doomed men.
I'm almost done.
Only one name left.
Go on.
(ARYA SIGHS)
The Hound.
-Thank you.
-Your mother always had a sweet tooth.
-Really?
-Oh. yes.
At suppertime.
she would go straight for honey cakes.
candied almonds. custard.
Anything sweet.
Eventually. your grandfather had
to assign a septa to watch her at meals.
Cat was the firstborn daughter
after all.
It was important
that she remain desirable
so Father could arrange
a good match for her
and she was starting to get fat.
My mother fat?
She never let me have my pudding
until I'd finished all my proper food.
This is before she married your father
and moved to the North.
By the time you were born.
your father's austerity had become hers.
Marriage changes people.
(GASPS)
I didn't mean for you to stop.
Go on. enjoy them.
-How do you like them?
-They're delicious.
Where did you get the lemons?
You can't grow them up here.
Oh. gods. no.
Petyr had three crates brought
all the way from King's Landing.
-He knew you liked lemon cakes.
-He's so kind.
He really cares for you.
Think where you'd be without him.
In their clutches and tried for murder.
Yes. I'm very lucky.
He feels responsible for you.
-Oh. I know he does. I'm so grateful.
-Why?
Why does he feel responsible for you?
Well. I'm half Tully.
He loved your family so much.
Loved your mother.
That's what you wanted to say.
He loves you. Aunt Lysa.
He's married to you.
Your mother never loved him. Never.
Cat always went straight
for the sweetest thing.
The most obvious thing.
Your Uncle Brandon.
Your handsome. arrogant.
cruel Uncle Brandon.
He almost killed Petyr in a duel.
And your mother loved him anyway.
And now Petyr is risking his life
to save you.
the daughter
of a woman who didn't love him
no more than those whores
in his brothels.
-Has he told you about them?
-No.
He hasn't told you about the vile
things they do with their bodies?
The vile things they let him do
with their bodies?
-No. never.
-Are you pregnant?
What? No. I told you.
Lord Tyrion and I never--
I wasn't asking about Tyrion.
What have you let Petyr do
with your body?
-Aunt Lysa. no. I--
-Your young. pretty body.
-Nothing. I'm a virgin.
-Don't lie to me.
You're hurting me.
I'll know if you lie.
I'm a virgin. I swear it.
He loves you. Aunt Lysa.
All he says is that I'm stupid.
I'm a stupid little girl
with stupid dreams
who never learns
and I'm a terrible liar.
so I should always tell the truth.
And I swear to you
that he has never touched me.
Not once. not ever.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
It's all right.
It will all be all right.
You'll be a widow soon.
They'll execute that dwarf
for murdering the king
and you'll be free to marry Robin.
You'll be the Lady of the Vale. Hmm?
(SANSA SIGHS)
(HORSE WHINNIES)
(GRUNTING)
Didn't they teach you
how to ride a horse?
Yes. my lady. when I was young.
There wasn't much call for it
with Lord Tyrion. though.
He preferred litters.
Perhaps you should have stayed with him.
It's not going to be
a pleasant journey for you.
It could take weeks to get to the Wall.
depending on the weather.
That's a long way off.
Well. Lady Sansa's brother's
at Castle Black.
If I were her. that's where I'd go.
Feel free to stop at any point.
Never. my lady. I'm your squire.
I've made it this far in the world
without a squire.
-I don't see why I need one now.
-All knights have squires. my lady.
I'm not a knight. And I'm not a slaver.
either. I don't own you.
I swore an oath. my lady.
I am releasing you from that oath.
That means you could leave.
I know.
What do you think will happen
if you leave?
They'll say I wasn't a very good squire.
(HORSE NICKERS. WHINNIES)
-The hell you doing?
-Practicing.
-What. ways to die?
-No one's going to kill me.
They will if you nance around like that.
That's no way to fight.
It's not fighting. It's water dancing.
Dancing?
Maybe you ought to put on a dress.
Who taught you that shite?
The greatest swordsman who ever lived.
Syrio Forel. the First Sword
to the Sealord of Braavos.
Braavos.
Greasy-haired little bastard. I bet.
-They all are.
-What do you know about anything?
I bet his hair is greasier
than Joffrey's cunt.
-It was not.
-Was? He dead?
Yes. He was killed.
-Who by?
-Meryn Trant. That's why Ser Meryn--
Meryn Trant?
The greatest swordsman who ever lived
killed by Meryn fucking Trant?
-He was outnumbered.
-Any boy whore with a sword
could beat three Meryn Trants.
Syrio didn't have a sword.
Or armor. Just a stick.
The greatest swordsman who ever lived
didn't have a sword?
(LAUGHS)
All right. You have a sword.
Let's see what he taught you.
Go on. do it for your Braavosi friend.
Dead like all the rest of your friends.
(GRUNTS)
Your friend's dead and Meryn Trant's not
'cause Trant had armor
and a big fucking sword.
(PANTING)
(BIRD CALLING)
Your Grace.
Prince Oberyn. Writing letters?
A poem. actually.
May I show you the gardens?
I couldn't very well refuse
a royal escort.
No. you couldn't.
I didn't realize you were a poet.
Not a very good one.
(CERSEI CHUCKLES)
For your paramour?
For one of my daughters.
You have several. don't you?
-Eight.
-Eight?
Eight daughters?
The fifth is difficult.
I named her after my sister. Elia.
Beautiful name.
Yes.
But I can't say it without turning sad.
And after I turn sad.
I grow angry.
Perhaps that's why she's difficult.
The gods love their stupid jokes.
don't they?
Which joke is that?
You're a prince of Dorne.
A legendary fighter.
A brilliant man
feared throughout Westeros.
But you could not save your sister.
I'm a Lannister. Queen for 19 years.
Daughter of the most powerful man alive.
But I could not save my son.
What good is power
if you cannot protect the ones you love?
We can avenge them.
Yes. we can avenge them.
You really believe
Tyrion murdered your son?
I know he did.
We will have a trial
and we will learn the truth.
We'll have a trial. anyway.
I haven't seen my daughter
in over a year.
The last time I saw her.
she was swimming with two
of my girls in the Water Gardens.
(CHUCKLES)
Laughing in the sun.
I want to believe that.
I want to believe she's happy.
You have my word.
We don't hurt little girls in Dorne.
Everywhere in the world.
they hurt little girls.
Would you bring her a gift for me?
I wasn't there for her name day.
I don't know when I'll see her again.
Anything at all.
The best shipwrights in King's Landing
have been working on it for months.
Myrcella loves the open water.
OBERYN: I will have it sailed
down to Sunspear for her.
Please tell her...
...her mother misses her very much.
PODRICK: Oh. no. no. no.
Hells.
Gods.
(SIGHS)
Did you remove the skin?
No. my lady.
Have you ever cooked a rabbit before?
Did you ever cook anything
for Lord Tyrion?
No. my lady.
That was the cooks.
(GROANS)
-What are you doing?
-I'm helping you with your armor.
I've been removing my own armor for
quite some time. thank you very much.
What exactly did you do for Lord Tyrion?
I brought him his meals and cleared
his table when he was finished.
I kept his clothing and linens clean.
Carried his messages
and returned the replies.
-Mostly I poured wine.
-Oh.
Whilst in Lord Tyrion's service.
did you ever do anything
remotely related to combat?
I killed a man.
Who?
A Kingsguard.
He tried to kill Lord Tyrion
at the Blackwater.
How did you kill a Kingsguard?
I pushed a spear
through the back of his head.
Bloody ridiculous.
Help me with these straps.
(WOMAN WHIMPERING. RAST LAUGHING)
RAST: Hey. Hey. get up.
Get up.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
MAN: That's it lad. put it inside.
Get the fire going again.
We're all freezing.
Aye. What we need is a girl there.
I've got to have a piss.
(PIGS GRUNTING)
(WOMEN WHIMPERING)
Now keep quiet.
(LANTERN RATTLES)
(LANTERN SQUEAKING)
(COUGHS)
You need water.
It doesn't matter.
Of course it matters.
You mustn't let anything stop you.
They already have stopped me.
No.
You're not here.
You're far from here.
What does that mean?
(CROWS CAWING)
At the hill.
A great weirwood tree.
You've seen it. too.
Meera and I. even Hodor.
we're only here to guide you.
(CROW CAWING)
He's waiting for you.
We have to find it.
You have to make it.
We will.
This-- this isn't the end.
Not for you.
Not yet.
MEERA: How...
will we know the end?
You'll know.
(FOOTSTEPS)
LOCKE: Brothers.
You do move quiet.
-How many?
-11 men.
Most of them already drunk.
No guards posted. They don't seem
to have a care in the world.
We'll carve them up like walnut pie.
Karl was a top paid cutthroat
in Flea Bottom.
I've seen what he can do with a knife.
Have you seen what I can do
with a knife?
Not yet.
There's a hut
on the west side of the keep.
-We should steer clear of it.
-Why?
They've got some hounds
chained up inside.
Closer we can get without the dogs
sniffing us. the better.
New moon tonight.
(SIGHS)
Get some rest.
We move at sundown.
I've always liked a girl with curls.
A touch of class.
You take whatever's left.
Get her up.
BRAN: Stop. Stop.
What are you doing?
HODOR: Hodor. Hodor. Hodor.
Stop. Stop!
-HODOR: Hodor. Hodor.
-BRAN: Stop!
-Please.
-Hodor.
-Please. get off her!
-Hodor. Hodor.
Please! Please. leave her alone!
BRAN: Please. stop. Stop.
-What are you doing? Leave her alone!
-Hodor. Hodor.
-No!
-Shh.
(GASPING)
(WHIMPERING)
You've got pretty hair. don't you?
Now what is a pretty
little highborn girl like you
doing out here
in the deep. dark woods. eh?
You left your daddy's castle
looking for trouble. didn't you?
No dresses for you.
You like it rough. don't you?
You like it in the gutter. don't you?
If you let my sister go. I can help you.
You can help me?
I can.
And how you gonna do that?
I have the sight. I can see things.
That's very helpful.
Things that haven't happened yet.
What a fine thing.
A fine thing.
Have you seen what I'm gonna do
to your sister?
Have you seen what they're going to do
No.
Don't close your eyes.
I saw you die tonight.
I saw your body burn.
I saw the snow fall and bury your bones.
MAN: To arms!
They're here. the Night's Watch.
(MEN SHOUTING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Rescue party is here. lads. Lady.
-Is Jon with you?
-Aye.
I'll take you to him.
You're Brandon Stark?
(GASPS)
Hodor. Hodor.
The little crippled lord.
We're going for a ride. boy.
Jon! Jon!
Keep talking
and I'll cut your friends' throats.
Starting with the idiot. Do you hear?
Do you hear?
HODOR: Hodor! Hodor!
Hodor. Hodor.
Hodor. Hodor. Hodor.
(HEAVY BREATHING. GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(NECK CRACKS)
Hodor.
BRAN: Hodor. get his knife.
Cut me loose.
-BRAN: Hodor. get his knife.
-Hodor.
Cut me loose. Hodor.
Jojen and Meera. free them.
Go!
(SWORDS CLANKING. MEN SHOUTING)
Jon.
Jon!
If he sees you.
he won't let you go north.
-He's my brother.
-And wants to protect you.
He'll take you back to Castle Black.
You have to decide.
Do you want to find
the three-eyed raven?
-BRAN: Hodor.
-HODOR: Hodor.
We need to free Summer.
And we need to go.
(SHOUTS. MAN GROANS)
Lord Snow.
Are you bringing me back for trial?
We had a good thing here.
We were free men.
You'll never be free.
You'll never know what that's like.
You learn how to fight in a castle?
(GROANS)
Some old man teach you how to stand.
how to parry?
(GROANS)
How to fight with honor?
You know what's wrong with honor?
(SPITS)
(GRUNTS)
You.
(GURGLING)
(PANTING)
Are you all right?
Come with me.
Come on.
(GRUNTS)
We lost four brothers?
Five.
What the seven hells could do that
to a man?
I count 10 dead mutineers.
Locke said there were 11 of them.
Where's Rast?
(WIND HOWLING)
(PANTING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(ROARING. RAST SCREAMS)
-Here's another.
-Jon.
JON: Where in seven hells?
Come here.
(DIREWOLF WHINING)
I missed you. boy.
What should we do with this lot?
It's not safe for you here on your own.
Mance Rayder has an army
heading this way
and there's worse out there than Mance.
Come with us to Castle Black.
We can find you work. Keep you safe.
Meaning all respect. Ser Crow.
Craster beat us and worse.
Your brother crows beat us and worse.
We'll find our own way.
You want to stay here
in Craster's Keep?
(SPITS)
Burn it to the ground
and all the dead with it.